Guide to the Center for Documentary Studies Double Take Exhibition Collection, 1906-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Center for Documentary Studies Double Take Exhibition collection 1906-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies.
5.0 linear feet Extent: 51 Items
The Center for Documentary Studies was established at Duke University in Durham, N.C. for the study of the documentary process. Collection contains black and white and color photographs that were on display at the Center for Documentary Studies. The photographs are from series that were published in DOUBLETAKE or by DoubleTake books between 1995-1997.
docstudiesexhibitioncoll
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Center for Documentary Studies Double Take Exhibition Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007.
Collection Overview
The Center for Documentary Studies Double Take Exhibition Collection contains black and white and color photographs that were on display at the Center for Documentary Studies. The photographs are from series that were published in DOUBLETAKE or by DoubleTake books between 1995-1997. Many were taken by photographers in the southern United States, but there are also images from Massachusetts, Illinois, and from countries such as Vietnam and Ireland.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Portrait photography -- United States; Photography -- United States -- History; Southern states -- Pictorial works; Black and white photographs
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2007 (2007-0157), (8 boxes)
  The Center for Documentary Studies Double Take Exhibition Collection contains black and white and color photographs that were on display at the Center for Documentary Studies. The photographs are from series that were published in DOUBLETAKE or by DoubleTake books between 1995-1997. Many were taken by photographers in the Southern U.S., but there are also images from Massachusetts, Illinois, and from countries such as Vietnam and Ireland.
  - Baseball Portrait, circa 1910, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 1/8 x 10 1/8") (Box 1)
    Photographer: Detroit Publishing Company.
    From A Whole World: dimensionss from the Detroit Publishing Collection, DoubleTake, Summer 1995.
    [child in baseball uniform ERIE]
  - Old Chain Bridge, Newbury Port, Massachusetts, circa 1906, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 x 10")
    From A Whole World: Pictures from the Detroit Publishing Collection, DoubleTake, Summer 1995.
    First suspension bridge in America.
  - Three-Cycle Compression Ship Engine, 1906, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 x 10")
  - A View From Suspension Bridge, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1906, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 1/8 x 10 1/8")
  - Tobin School, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 x 10")
    Photographer: Nixon, Nicholas.
    From the series Room 306, DoubleTake, Spring 1996.
    Back of print: Joel Geiger, Perkins School for the Blind 1992. 11/50
  - Hanging Out Front, Plano, Texas, 1994, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 x 9 7/8")
    Photographer: Richards, Patricia D.
    From the series Scenes from Early Morn Drive: Teen Years, published in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - Gas Station At Night, Dubuque, Iowa, April 1940, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 x 10")
    Photographer: Vachon, John.
    From DoubleTake, Winter 1997
    Reproduced from the collections of the Library of Congress.
  - USS Iowa, 1988, (color; dimensions: 9 x 12") (Box 2)
    Photographer: Grimes, Tom.
    From DoubleTake, Fall 1996.
  - Chinese New Year, Los Angeles, California, February 1996, (color; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: Humble, John.
    From DoubleTake, Winter 1997.
  - Carlos Pretending To Fix Little Man's Hair For The Photograph, White Furniture Company, Mebane, North Carolina, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14") (Box 3)
    Photographer: Bamberger, Bill.
    From From Closing: The Life and Death of an American Factory,, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1998.
  - Melissa Retouching Table Leg, Finishing Department, White Furniture Company, Mebane, North Carolina, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
  - Behind Hugh’s House [boy with glasses running through alleyway], West Belfast, Winter 1995, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: Cahill, Christina.
    From DoubleTake, Summer 1997.
  - Kevin & Maria, West Belfast, Winter 1995, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
  - Sonia with Mary Claire, Tribeca Park, New York City, 1995, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: Duffy, Pamela.
    From the series Nanny, DoubleTake, Spring 1997
  - Grandparents’ Fiftieth Anniversary Party [elderly woman opening gift], Salisbury, North Carolina, 1994, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: McMahon, Connette Pearl.
    From the series Family and Friends, a student project from the course American Communities: A Documentary Approach, 1994, published in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W. W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - Counselor with Camper, Camp New Hope, Orange County, North Carolina, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 13 7/8")
    Photographer: Paul, Gregory.
    From the series New Hope, DoubleTake, Summer 1997
    Supported by the 1993 John Hope Franklin Award.
  - Free-Play Time, Camp New Hope, Orange County, North Carolina, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 13 7/8")
  - [man and baby sitting], Lindenself Commune, Roxboro, North Carolina, 1979, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: Sanders, Kim.
    From a student project in the course American Communities: A Documentary Approach, 1979, published in DoubleTake, Winter 1997.
  - [telephone booth], Knoxville, Tennessee, 1994, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 13 3/4")
    Photographer: Steinmetz, Mark.
    From the series At the Edge of the City, in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - Evanston, Illinois, 1988, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 13 7/8")
    From the series Little League, DoubleTake, Spring 1997.
  - [scoreboard on chain link fence], Evanston, Illinois, 1988, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 13 3/4")
  - [Mennonites in dust storm], Mexican Mennonites’ Valley of Roses Campo, Nuevo Ideal Colony, Durango, Mexico, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
    Photographer: Towell, Larry.
    From DoubleTake, Summer 1995.
    '97 - on back of print.
  - [street corner], Dubuque, Iowa, 1940, (black and white print; dimensions: 11 x 14")
  - [people sitting around table], Commercial Bank, Duluth, Minnesota, 1995, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: Ahlgren, Steven.
    From the series Corporate Documents, DoubleTake, Summer, 1997.
  - Neta and Gigi, Lake Placid, Florida, 1993, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: Beck, Fran Bitett.
    From the series Relationships, in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - Shana, Chimayo, New Mexico, 1996, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: Berridge, Mary.
    From the series Portraits: Women Living with HIV, DoubleTake, Summer 1997.
  - Laughing Boy, Little Village Neighborhood, Chicago, Illinois, 1996, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: D’Amato, Paul.
    From the series Barrio Workers, DoubleTake, Summer 1997.
  - Dr. Bruce Soloway with his patient Nayda Burgos, Bronx-Lebanon Hospital, New York City, [July] 1995, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: Levin, Meryl.
    From Beyond the Emergency Room, DoubleTake, Sprint 1997.
  - Christmas Tree Delivery, New York City, 1993, (color; dimensions: 16 x 20")
    Photographer: Mermelstein, Jeff.
  - In the [Shanghai] Station, 1993, (color; dimensions: 16 x 19 7/8")
    Photographer: Temple, Charlotte.
  - [man seated with woman leaning on his shoulder], (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 19 3/4") (Box 5)
    Photographer: Berndt, Jerry.
    From the series Barroom, DoubleTake, Fall 1996.
  - [profile of two men], (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 20")
  - Jeffersonville, Indiana, Looking Toward Louisville, Kentucky, 1996, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 3/4 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Borowiec, Andrew.
    From the series Along the Ohio, DoubleTake, Summer 1997.
  - ROTC girls, Sanford, 1996, (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 18 1/2")
    Photographer: Breitenbach, Eric.
    From the series Photographs from Florida, 1989-94, in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W. W. Norton & Company, 1997.
    Front of print - Sanford; back of print - Sandford.
  - Triathlete, Lake Mary, 1990, (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 18 1/2")
  - Carlos, Andrea, and Ivonne, Los Angeles, California, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 20 1/4")
    Photographer: DeCesare, Donna.
  - [man on phone in messy office], (black and white print; MNat: 14 x 14 3/8")
    Photographer: Friedlander, Lee.
    From the series The Dreyfus Fund Portraits, DoubleTake, Summer 1995.
  - [man with freckles], Walden Pond, Concord, Massachusetts, 1990, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 3/4 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Kennard, John.
    From the series Walden Ponders, DoubleTake, Spring 1997.
  - [people on the beach], Walden Pond, Concord, Massachusetts, 1990, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 7/8 x 19 3/4")
  - [family portrait on a Ford], Vance County, North Carolina, 1988, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 3/4 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Moses, John.
    From DoubleTake, Winter 1997, and The Youngest Parents, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - View From The Subway, Brooklyn, New York, 1991, (black and white print; dimensions: 16 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Roma, Thomas.
    From the series Come Sunday, DoubleTake, Winter 1996.
  - Sunday School Classroom, Monroe, Louisiana, 1993, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 7/8 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Sartor, Margaret.
    From the series Stealing Home, DoubleTake, Fall 1996.
    On back of print: FxT1, signed by photographer and dated '98.
  - Mennonite Children in Schoolyard, Lancaster, Pennsylvania, 1968, (black and white print; dimensions: 8 3/4 x 13 3/8")
    Photographer: Tice, George.
    From the series Fields of Peace, DoubleTake, Spring 1997.
    Print: 5/29/90, print is adhered to a thick paper.
  - Eduardo, James, and Arturo on the way to pick tobacco, Four Oaks, North Carolina, 1991, (black and white print; dimensions: 15 1/4 x 19 3/4")
    Photographer: Whetstone, Jeff.
  - Glenda Hollis, Birmingham, Alabama, 1992, (black and white print; Mat: 20 x 24") (Box 6)
    Photographer: Springer, Melissa.
    From DoubleTake, Summer 1996.
  - My Aunt Betty’s Kitchen Floor, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1994, (color; dimensions: 20 x 24") (Box 7)
    Photographer: DuBois, Doug.
    From the series Mining Avella, DoubleTake, Winter 1997.
    On back of print: 97.
  - Mary Poppins, Gretna, Louisiana, 1993, (color; dimensions: 20 x 24")
    Photographer: Greiner, William K.
    From DoubleTake, Spring 1996, and the series Homefront, in A New Life: Stories and Photographs from the Suburban South, Lyndhurst Series on the South, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
  - Thigh Cream, Metairie, Louisiana, 1994, (color; dimensions: 20 x 24")
  - The Uncommon Covergirl, Hither Hills [State Park], Montauk, New York, 1991, (color; dimensions: 20 x 30") (Box 8)
    Photographer: Bartos, Adam.
    From the series Hither Hills, DoubleTake, Spring 1997.
  - [Four] Ho Chi Minh Statues, Hanoi, Vietnam, 1994, (color; dimensions: 20 x 29 1/2")
    Photographer: Epstein, Mitch.
    From DoubleTake, Fall 1995, and Vietnam: A Book of Changes, DoubleTake Books in association with W.W. Norton & Company, 1997.
    7/14/97 on back of print.